



# Elizabeth C. Robertson

Attorney

Liz Robertson advises and defends public school districts on a broad range of legal issues, with a particular emphasis on special education, free speech, and labor and employment. Liz also has experience negotiating collective bargaining agreements with public sector labor unions using both traditional and interest-based models of bargaining.

### **CONTACT**

Tel (206) 622-0203 Fax (206) 223-2003 elizabeth@pfrwa.com

# PROFESSIONAL POSITIONS

Attorney, Porter Foster Rorick, 2019-present

Judicial Clerk, Washington State Court of Appeals, Division II (Hon. Linda CJ Lee), 2017-19

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Arizona James E. Rogers College of Law, Tucson, Arizona, J.D., magna cum laude, 2017 Articles Editor, *Arizona Law Review* 

University of Arizona Eller College of Management, Tucson, Arizona, B.S., with honors, 2012

## PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

Washington Council of School Attorneys

# AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Special education
- Public records/FERPA
- Appeals

- Collective bargaining
- Employee discipline and discharge
- First Amendment

#### PRACTICE HIGHLIGHTS

- Negotiated successful resolution of collective bargaining agreements with certificated and classified school employees in public school districts throughout Washington including Federal Way, Tukwila, Port Townsend, Union Gap, Selah, and North Franklin.
- Int'l Union of Operating Eng'rs, Local 302 v. Puyallup Sch. Dist. (2022). Prevailed in arbitration challenging termination of employee for violations of district's civility policy.
- Drafted successful motion to intervene and modify civil protection order, establishing school district's authority to determine the "comparable educational services" provided to a student precluded from attending school due to a civil protection order.
- In re Bremerton Sch. Dist., 2020-SE-0177 (OAH 2021). Prevailed on all issues in special education due process hearing, successfully defending school district against alleged Child Find violation.
- Coupe v. Port Townsend Sch. Dist. No. 50, Jefferson County Superior Court Cause No. 20-2-00108-16 (2021). Successfully obtained summary judgment order dismissing former employee's wrongful termination claim based upon the employee's failure to exhaust contractual remedies.
- Tukwila Educ. Ass'n v. Tukwila Sch. Dist., Decision 13314 (EDUC, 2021). Obtained dismissal of unfair labor practice complaint alleging interference based on the district's denial of union access to building staff meetings.
- Successfully defended school district in multiple grievance arbitrations involving caseload and staffing of special education programs within the district.
- In re Shoreline Sch. Dist., 2019-SE-0157 (OAH 2019) (affirmed on appeal, W.D. Wash. 2021). Drafted successful motion for summary judgment, obtaining order overriding parent's refusal to consent to an initial evaluation for special education services.

### SELECTED PRESENTATIONS AND PUBLICATIONS

- Editor, Washington School Law Update, 2021-present.
- "Bargaining Law 101," 21<sup>st</sup> Century Bargaining Skills Workshop, Washington School Personnel Association, January 2022.
- "Student Discipline Refresher for School Administrators (Special Education)," Tumwater School District, August 2022.
- "Public Records Disclosure: A Practical Workshop," all-client annual training, 2021-22.
- "Off the Clock? Public Employee Free Speech in an Era of Social and Political Unrest," Washington School Personnel Association, October 2021.
- "Parental Authority in Schools: Who has it and Why it Matters," Washington School Personnel Association, March 2020.
- Elizabeth Robertson, *Diagnosing Amaral: Mental Health Conditions as Newly Discovered Evidence*, 58 Ariz. L. Rev. 1165 (2016).